NAZIMUDDIN Phone: 510-896-0333

Email: nazimuddinengg@gmail.com

#### SUMMARY

Customer-focused Desktop Support with over 5 years of experience with a broad spectrum of computer operating systems applications and hardware. Exceptional customer service and communication skills; consistently conveys competence and concern to end users. Strong ability to effectively multitask and to perform with a sense of urgency for rapid issue resolution

Strategic Thinker with ability to analyze problem and provide well-researched solutions Dynamic Team Player with integrative thinking skills and analytical skills Quick Learner with ability to learn new tools and technologies easily Excellent communication, presentation, and interpersonal skills

## Highlights:

- · Microsoft Office expert
- · Computer Science Fundamentals
- · Customer Interface Skills
- · Strong understanding of TCP/IP concepts
- · Experience with Cisco networking
- · Troubleshooting Proficiency

- · Software Development Life Cycle
- · Customer Service Skills
- · Quality Assurance
- · Documentation & reporting
- · Vast technical knowledge
- · Exceptional telephone etiquette
- · Fluent in English, Hindi, Punjabi, Telugu.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Pacific Gas and Electric IT Desktop Support

SAN ROMAN CALIFORNIA July 2019 - Present

- Responded to requests for technical assistance in person via phone and remotely for the following technologies: Windows and Mac OS based end points (Laptops Desktops & Thin Clients) Tablets & Smartphones (IOS & Android) and Microsoft Office
- Assisted the Help Desk Manager in supervision training and mentorship of student employees at the Help Desk with a specific focus on leading the team of Desktop Support Referral student employees who also contribute to tier 2 ticket resolution
- Continually updated personal knowledge of computing hardware operating systems and software
- Maintained confidentiality and discretion when working with passworded or sensitive materials
- Video conferencing support (Zoom & Blue Jeans) and Active Directory- Adding & deleting user accounts

#### BASIC SOLUTIONS INC

MILPITAS, CALIFORNIA Jan 2017 – Apr 2019

# IT Desktop Support

- · Experience in job scheduling and backup management
- · Install, upgrade, configure and support for end user workstation hardware and software
- · Diagnose and troubleshoot hardware and software problems for end users
- · Experience in providing customer support through service desk
- Maintain software and hardware inventories
- · Perform critical Incident Management for the priority issues
- · Actively participated in an activity and change management on the servers and networks
- · Performing daily reports to check the status of servers and networks
- · Create weekly and monthly trending reports around availability and capacity
- · Provided day to day analysis to the top management to keep them apprised of the Major incidents in the environments
- · Experience in using ITSM Service Now tool for incident, Service request, Change and problem management
- · Experience infrastructure monitoring tools
- · Experience in desktop imaging

- · Understanding and troubleshooting issues with windows servers
- · Troubleshooting on desktops, laptops, printers
- · Knowledge in SCCM and remote tools
- · Hands on experience using Microsoft Office

#### SILICON VALLEY UNIVERSITY

#### MILPITAS, CALIFORNIA

**Apr 2015 – Dec 2016** 

# IT Support Graduate Assistant

- · Install desktop computers, software, peripherals, printers, and other technology solutions
- · Troubleshoot and resolve issues for a wide range of technology support issues
- · Perform customer service to users of campus technology
- · Assist in building, testing, and maintaining the campus standard builds for Windows and Mac Operating systems on campus
- · Troubleshoot and resolve issues in IT
- · Perform some administration tasks related to operating systems and software
- · Video Conferencing experience with Polycom, Cisco and other video conferencing equipment providers. Familiarity with applications for PC, Mac, Android, iOS
- · Web Conferencing Good knowledge of MS LiveMeeting, NetMeeting, GO TO MEETING, TeamViewer and Polycom web streaming applications and technologies.

#### TATABUSINESS SUPPORT SERVICES

HYDERABAD, INDIA

## **Sr Customer Service Executive**

Apr 2014 - Mar 2015

- · Proven experience providing customer support in busy call center environments for public utility and insurance industry employers.
- · To Answer queries/resolve problems of customers through Inbound calls and if required up sell/ cross sell.
- · Attend **Inbound & Outbound calls**, sometime respond through email and chat to customers.
- · Ability to up sell/cross sell. Serves as a basic point of contact for customers with complaints, queries, request, feedbacks etc.
- · Prepares **daily reports** on the daily activities of Customer Care team.
- · Ensures that all the request, queries and complaint of customer are responded in a timely and professional manner.
- · Develops as well as maintains the relationship with external parties.
- Responsible for proper scrutiny and recording of the complaints received from customers.

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science, Major in Computer Science Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science Engineering

December 2016 May 2013

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

- · Software Methodologies: Agile Methodology, Waterfall Methodology
- · Office Applications: **MS Office**, **JIRA**, Office 365, Outlook, Microsoft Word, Excel, Spreadsheet, and PowerPoint

Operating Systems: Windows7/ 2000/XP, MAC OS, LINUX
Networking: TCP/IP, HTTP, Security, Firewall, OSI Model, LAN, WAN

· Networking protocols: TCP, UDP, DNS